So first I wanna say hi to extention school.
首先我想向进修学院的同学问声好
We have 350 students watching our lecture every day.
每天都有350名学生观看讲座
So I wanna say hi to them.
我想向他们问声好
And actually I want to especially invite extention school
我想特别邀请进修学院的同学
and everybody here to see our very modest Tal- right?-
及在座的各位来听谦逊的Tal
he didn't tell us he was on 60 Minutes,but that is OK.
他没告诉我们他上了《60分钟时事杂志》 但没关系
But Saturday night,
但周六晚上
Tal is going to be the honerary basketball coach
Tal将担任女子队
for the women's team,
荣誉篮球教练
which- the game against Cornell on Saturday at 7 o'clock,
周六晚七点对抗Cornell大学队
which is the biggest game of the season...
那是本赛季最重要的比赛
Six? Six o'clock on Saturday. The biggest game of the season.
六点吗？周六晚六点 本赛季最重要的比赛
We actually wanna see everyone of you here
希望能见到在座的每一位
and everybody at the extention school at the game.
及进修学院的同学去观赛
Extention students,I'll have free tickets for you.
进修学院的同学们 我有免费票给你们
Well,most of you- a hundred of you.
有一百张票
So in honor of that,
以示敬意
we have an honorary student and an honorary team which is,
我们有可敬的同学和可敬的球队
our very famous Kathy Delaney-Smith,award-winning,
著名的Kathy Delaney-Smith 获奖的
the most fabulous coach in a whole nation and...
国内最著名的教练
our women's basketball team is here! Come on now!
女子篮球队也在这里 上来
These are our honorary students. There you go. They are shy.
这就是可敬的同学们 上来 她们害羞
Alright,so come! Come and see them!
来吧 上来 见见大家
And actually I'll be there with all my friends and families.
我会和所有朋友和家人去观战
And Tal will sign your hand.
Tal会在你们的手上签名
Alright! Ready guys? (One player: Yeah.)
好 准备好了吗  好了
This is the biggest game.
这是最重要的比赛
These are the Ivy League Champs last year!
她们是去年的长青藤联盟冠军
Alright. Give 'em a throw. Throw 'em out. Throw 'em out!
好 把礼物扔出去吧 扔出去吧
Go! Go! Go! Let's go! Go! Go! Let's go! Hahaha.
扔 快扔 快扔
Alright. Thank you.
好的 谢谢你们
Thanks. I'll see you all on Saturday. Good luck. Thanks.
谢谢 周六见 祝你们好运 谢谢
OK. I didn't plan this,but... (Tal blows a whistle.) Alright.
好 这不是我安排的 好啦
Alright,do I have anything else? Oh. OK.
好的 身上还有别的东西吗？好
Thank you .And thank you.
谢谢你们 也感谢你们
And we are going to continue talking about gratitude.
我们继续谈"感激"
So... Last time,I ended by talking about my role model-
那么...上次课结束时我讲到我的榜样
the person who to me exemplifies,
我的一个典范
more than anyone else what a true benefit finder is.
比任何人都重要 一个真正的积极者
And when I told about my grandmother,I told the...
当我谈到我的祖母时 我说...
I told you how she wasn't ignoring what wasn't working,
我告诉你们她并不无视无益的东西
she wasn't ignoring the evil,the bad,the negative in her life.
她并不无视邪恶 坏的 生命中消极的东西
However,the same time,she refused to ignore the positive.
但同时 她也拒绝无视积极的东西
In other words,what she insisted on was staying real.
换言之 她坚持保持现实
Being real. Being connected to what was around her.
现实地生活 与周遭保持联系
And when it was evil and bad,
当周遭充满邪恶的坏的东西
she was connected to that and at the same time,
她与之保持联系 与此同时
she was also connected to the good.
她也与好的东西保持联系
Benefit finder is not about being a detached Pollyanna.
积极者不是盲目乐观的人
Far from it. The question we asked last time-
区别很大 我们上次提出的问题
and I want to end the lecture today on gratitude
我想以"感激"结束今天的讲座
before we move on to change- was: one,
然后开始讲"改变" 第一是
why are not more people benefit finders?
为什么没有更多的积极者?
Why are more people not optimistic?
为什么没有更多的人保持乐观?
I mean,you saw the research. People live longer.
大家看到研究 人们活得更长
They are happier,healthier,more successful.
更快乐 更健康 更成功
Why isn't everyone a benefit finder?
为什么不是人人都是积极者？
Why aren't we all optimists?
为什么我们不都是乐观主义者？
If it pays,
如果它是有回报的
in both the ultimate currency- the currency of happiness
用终极货币形式 以幸福来回报
as well as in hard currency- success currency?
也用硬货币来 以成功来回报？
Why are not more people benefit finders?
为什么没有更多的积极者？
And the answer to that was,to great extent,
问题的答案 在很大程度上
because of the media.
是因为媒体的原故
What we have in the media is magnifying,zooming in,
媒体正在放大 聚焦
magnifying the negative,maximizing it,
放大消极的东西 使其最大化
having it take the entire screen,the entire page,
由它占据整个屏幕 整个版面
while minimizing the positives.
同时最小化积极的东西
And in many ways,the media makes fault finders out of us.
在很多方面 媒体把我们变成消极者
And we need to counter that. How do we counter that?
而我们需要反击 如何反击？
On the macro level,by having good news channels,for example.
宏观层面上可以收看好的新闻频道
On the micro level,by having more inspiring art.
微观层面上可以培育富有启发性的艺术
Art throughout history has changed the world-
艺术在历史进程中改变了世界
whether it was during the dark ages,
不论是在黑暗年代
at the transition to the Renaissance,
在向文艺复兴过度的时期
whether it was during 18th and 19th century with Romantic artists
或者是在18和19世纪兴起的浪漫艺术家
and paving the road to freedom,
致力铺设通向自由之路
whether it was in mid 1930s and 40s with the Renaissance
亦或是上世纪三四十年代
in many ways of Hollywood,bringing more hope to people.
好莱坞的复兴 带给人们更多希望
So art plays a very important role,
艺术扮演着非常重要的角色
and hopefully,will continue to do so.
希望能继续如此
So then we talked about the global level,the macro level.
然后我们谈到大的层面 宏观层面
On the micro level,
在微观层面上
we talked about not waiting for bad things to happen,
我们谈到不要坐等坏事发生
for tragedy,
不要等悲剧
for something external to happen for us to be grateful.
或等外界有事发生 我们才知感激
Because when we are grateful,by definition,
因为我们感激 就其定义而言
we don't take something for granted.
就是不以某事为理所当然
And we shared the readings and the research on gratitude.
我们还分享了有关"感激"的文章及研究
The key,when doing it,when doing this exercise-
做这个修习的关键
and as I said,I do it every single day.
正如我所说 我每天都在做
I've done it since 19th of September,1999.
从1999年9月19日开始
Every single day. Religiously.
每一天 都进行信仰修习
The key to doing it and not taking this exercise for granted
修习的关键 不将此修习视为理所当然
is by maintaining freshness through-
是一直保持新鲜感
if you want to do it once a week,
如果你想每周做一次
it's better to do it once a week mindfully
每周一次用心去做
than doing it every day and taking it for granted.
比每天去做并将之视为理所当然要好
And OK check- did that. But ideally,you want to do it every day.
好的 做过了 但最理想的是每天做
Because by doing it every day,that's when you form a habit.
因为每天去做才能养成习惯
That's when you transform your thinking.
那样才能改变思维
And if you do it every day,the key is to vary,
每天去做的话 关健是要有变化
to think about different aspect every day,
每天思考不同的方向
to think about different aspects of your family
思考家人的不同方面
if you write family every day.
如果你每天都给家人写信
To write about work one week. To write about home the next week.
一周讲述工作 下一周写家庭
Maintaining mindfulness,
每次都要用心
focusing on things you didn't notice before,
专注以前没有注意过的事情
creating novel distinctions,as Ellen Langer would say.
发现新的特点 Ellen Langer如是说
And visualize-
并在脑中想像
so when you are thinking about your girlfriend or boyfriend,
当你想到你的女或男朋友
and writting your gratitude,visualize them.
书写感激之情时 在脑海中想像他们
When you are thinking about the meal
当你想到
that you just had in your dinning hall which was delicious,
刚在食堂吃过的一顿美味可口的饭时
think about it. Visualize it. Make it as real as possible.
想它 在脑海中想像 让它变得尽可能真实
That's how children think.
孩子就是这样思考
And that's why children have this freshness on the day to day-
所以孩子们每天都感觉新鲜
they don't take anything for granted. They see life as a miracle.
他们不把任何东西视为理所当然 他们视生命为奇迹
You know,Emerson once said,
爱默生曾经说过
"if the stars would shine once in a thousand years,
"如果星星每千年闪烁一次
we would all look up and praise the glory of this world.
我们都会仰视赞美这个世界的美丽
But because they shine every day,we take them for granted."
但是因为它们每天都在闪烁 我们将之视为理所当然"
For children,that dosen't exist.
在孩子眼中不存在理所当然
And part of the reason why it dosen't exist
其中的一个原因
is that because they don't think automatically,conceptually.
是因为他们不会自动地概念性地思考
They think more perceptually. Or sensually.
他们的思维是感知感性的
And they remain connected to the real.
他们和现实保持联系
And we can do it simply by visualizing.
通过在脑海中想像 我们就能做到
This is a wonderful research done here,
这项杰出研究完成于这里
William James Hall,8th floor.
就在William James大楼的八楼
The key to this,as to any change that we'll talk about-
做到"感激" 及实现即将谈到的"改变"的关键
we are going to devote more than two lectures to change today
我们会用超过两次讲座专门谈"改变"
as well as the whole of next week-
利用今天和下周整周
the key is to do it. To just do it. There are no short cuts.
关键是去做 亲力亲为 没有捷径
It's not because you've been through a lecture on gratitude
不是因为你们听了有关"感激"的讲座
and you understand,
你们理解
you really understand what a benefit finder means.
你们真正理解积极者的含义
That dosen't...
那不会...
That will not in and of itself make you a benefit finder.
仅仅理解不会让你成为积极者
You need to do it. You need to experience it.
你需要去做 需要去经历
And it's only through that,that over time,over time,
只有这样 经过一段时间
you'll begin to see more and more of the positive in the world
你才能开始越来越多地看到世界的积极方面
and counter the current schema
才能反击当下禁锢着
that most of us have literally been imprisoned by,
大多数人的思维方式
the fault finder schema.
也就是消极者的思维
William James in 1890,
William James在1890年
said that it takes about 21 days to change a habit.
说过需要21天改变一个习惯
It's probably a little bit optimistic.
可能有点过于乐观
May take a little bit longer. But try for 21 days.
可能需要更长时间 但不妨尝试21天
See what happens. You know there are some people.
看会怎样 有些人
I know some of you have already started this after last class.
我知道有些人已经在上次课后开始尝试
Some people see the benefits immediatly
有些人立即见到益处
and then you know the benefits may go away.
当然益处可能会消失
And then they see the benefits again six months later.
然后又在六个月后出现
But try. Try it for at least 21 days. At least a month.
但尝试一下 起码尝试21天或一个月
Next week is going to be your task
这也是你们下周的任务
as part of your weekly assignment.
作为每周任务的一部分
But start today. Don't wait. No other way to change. Because
从今天开始 不要等 实现改变没有他法
what you are doing is gradually chipping away the excess stone.
因为你所做的是一点点凿掉多余的石头
That excess stone,that limitation that has been put on us
那多余的石头 那些强加给我们的限制
by the schema all around us,
例如通过周围的观念
by the news that you read this morning,by most conversations,
通过今早读到的新闻 大多数的交谈
internal conversations that go on
还有内心的审视
as well as the external conversations.
以及外在的交谈等等
And what you are doing,
你所做的事
when you are doing this simple exercise,
当你做这个简单的修习时
the reason why it works so well-
它如此有效的原因
remember people who do it regularly and mindfully are happier,
记往经常用心修习的人更快乐
healthier,or more generous and benevolent,more successful.
更健康 更宽容 更和蔼 更成功
The reason why it works is because
修习行之有效的原因是因为
what you are doing is chisel by chisel,
你所做的事是一凿一凿地
chipping away the excess stone.
削走多余的石头
In my book,I talked about O'Hart Cummin,
在我的书中 我谈到O'Hart Cummin
my teacher and I've spoken to him...
我的导师 在课堂上
about him a few times in the class.
也谈到过他几次
He told me a story once
他曾经给我讲过一个故事
when he was not much older than most of you-
在他不比你们大多少的时候
he was in his mid-20s,left Israel to...
在他20来岁时 离开以色列
He was living in Europe for a few years and ended up in Holland.
他在欧洲生活了几年 最后住在荷兰
And after a while,he found himself homeless,
过了一段时间后 他变得无家可归
literally living under a tree,cold- it was the winter,
住在一棵树下面 寒冷难耐 当时是冬天
penniless- didn't have any money and without any friends.
身无分文 没有一分钱 也没有朋友
Absolutely miserable. And somehow for some reason,he said OK.
悲惨极了 然而出于某种原因 他说 好吧
He was in this depression for a few weeks and he said,
他抑郁了几周时间 然后他说
"well,let me try something."
"我不如试试"
Took out a piece of paper and on this piece of paper,
拿出一张纸 在这张纸上
simply wrote everything for which he was grateful.
写下让他感激的一切
So the kind of things he wrote there,as he told me:
他写下来的东西包括 他说
Beethoven's fifth- he loves music.
有贝多芬第五交响曲 他酷爱音乐
He wrote his parents,who were in Israel.
他写下在以色列的父母
He wrote vanilla icecream,which until today is his favorite.
他写下香草冰淇淋 至今仍是他的最爱
He thought about his friends back home.
他想到家乡的朋友们
All the things- he made a long list of all the things
所有这些事 他写了长长的一个名单
in the world for which he is grateful for.
写下世上让他感激的事物
And he credits this experience as the turning point in his life.
他将那次经历视为他人生的转折点
Why? Because he started to focus on something else.
为什么? 因为他开始专注于别的事物
Not just on the impossibilities,on the terrible,
不再对无奈可悲的处境耽耽于怀
but on the possibilities,the wonderful.
而是专注于各种可能和美好的事物
Do the experi...
大家也来试试
And by the way,he has this- he's now 55 years old.
随便说一句 他现在55岁了
He has this piece of paper with him,crumbled but still there,
仍随身携带这张纸 虽已褶皱
in his wallet,reminding him that there is so much,
但仍装在他的钱包里 提醒他
so so many wonderful things in the world.
世上有太多美好的事物
Just think about the kind of life that we are leading.
想想我们所过的生活
Back only 200 years ago,
就在200年前
who could afford to listen to their favorite musicians,
谁有钱听最爱的音乐家的演奏
or to watch their favorite actors,favorite plays?
欣赏最爱的演员的表演 最爱的戏剧?
Who could affor to do it? Only royalty.
谁有钱做那些事? 只有王室
And even them- they were limited,
即使是他们也不能随心所欲
in terms of which musician was in town
只能看在城里的音乐家演奏
or what players were in town.
只能看逗留在城里的演员
Today,we have literally the tip of our finger,
今天这一切都在我们的指尖上
whether it's on our MP3 or our DVD player.
在我们的MP3和DVD播放机上
Imagine... Just think about the luxury that we are living in.
想像...想想我们的奢侈生活
Kings and Queens that not lived that kind of luxury.
国王和王后也望尘莫及
However,we get used to it. We adapt.
然而我们习惯了 我们适应了
And sometimes it's a good thing,
有时这是件好事
because we also adapt to difficult experiences.
因为我们也适应困难的经历
And the question is how do we learn in a sense to (12:47),
问题是我们如何学会
meaning to adapt to the painful
学会适应痛苦
but not to remain impervious or to become impervious?
但又不被伤害或变得容易受伤害?
To become indifferent to the privilege that we have.
变得漠视我们所有的特权
How do we maintain the gratefulness? And it's by being mindful.
如何才能保持感激之情?那就是要用心
By thinking about those wonderful things that we have,
思考我们拥有的美好的东西
whether it's in a friend,
不论是在朋友身上
whether it's in a movie we want to watch,
在一部我们想看的电影中
whether it's in the lunch
或是过一会
we are going to have served to us in our house later.
食堂提供的午餐
The gratitude exercise- one of the reasons why it's so powerful-
感激修习如此有用的一个原因
because what we are doing is we are cocreating a reality.
因为我们所做的是共同创造一个现实
Most of the questions that
我们问得最多
we ask or are asked of us is "what's wrong?",
或被问及最多的问题是"哪里不对了?"
"what needs to be improved?","what are my weakness areas?"
"有什么需要改进的?""我的弱点是什么?"
Important questions- not enough.
这远远不是重要的问题
If these are the only questions
如果这些问题
that we ask as far as we are concerned,good does not exist.
是我们唯一提出或关心的 那么好的事物是不存在的
And when we ask "what are my grateful for?",
当我们问"我要感激什么?"时
even it's just once a day,
即使每天只问一次
that in and of itself creates- (A student sneezes)Bless you.
这么做的本身创造了...祝你身体健康
That in and of itself creates a new reality.
这么做的本身创造了一种新的现实
And we begin to see things that we haven't before.
让我们开始看到曾经无视的东西
So when I do this exercise
我在做这样的修习时
and I have been doing it for a long time,
我已经修习了很长时间
I notice things today that I wouldn't have noticed,
今天我才会注意到不做修习时
had not been doing this. And I would say,
忽视的事物 我会说
"oh,this is something I am going to write tonight.
"今晚我要写一写这样东西
It's so beautiful."
它是那么美好"
You know,when I go for a drive
开车兜风时
and see sunday night mountains in Hampshires,
看到笼罩在周日夜色中的Hampshires的群山
I'm going to write this down later.
晚上我要记下它
It's... And I wouldn't have noticed it.
没有修习我不会注意到它
And as far as I was concerned,these things did not exist,
就我而言 这些东西是不存在
just like the children on the bus did not exist,
就像公交车上的小孩子不存在一样
while you are not asking also the right question.
当你没有问对问题时
It's important to express gratitude obviously
显然表达感激也是重要的
not just to ourselves,but also to others.
不仅仅对自己 也要对他人
A lot of research on that too.
这方面也有很多研究
This was done by- you are reading or you have read- the paper
这是...你们正在或已经读过
by Seligman talking about expressing gratitude to others,
Seligman的有关向他人表达感激的论文
whether it's in the form of a letter or a visit or phone call.
可以是写信表达 拜访或致电
And the key of expressing gratitude-
表达感激的关键
this is not just a thank you note.
这不是一张简单的"感谢字条"
Dear Mom,thank you for being so great.Love,me.
亲爱的妈妈 感谢你如此伟大 爱你的儿子
That's not just a thank you note.
那不只是简单的感谢字条
It's sitting down and thinking,
它需要坐下来思考
"what can I be grateful for,for my mom?
"我能感激妈妈什么?
What has she done to me?
她都为我做了什么?
What has she given me throughout these years?"
这些年来 她给与了我哪些?"
And really thinking about it. Or really thinking a thing,
认真地去思考 认真思考
"what this teacher from 3rd grade do for me?"
"三年级的老师都为我做了什么?"
Not just talking to my friends,
不是跟朋友聊天时说
"I have a wonderful English teacher in 3rd grade."
"三年级时我有个很棒的英语老师"
But sitting down and thinking. What am I grateful for?
坐下来认真思考 我要感激什么?
What did she or he do for me
她或他都为我做了什么
that has contributed so much to my life,to who I am today?
对我的人生帮助良多 让我成为今天的我?
Or my roommate who always goes out of his or her way to help.
我的室友总是尽其所能帮我
I am really grateful. And to think about it.
我真得很感激 要去静思
Not just to,you know- at the end of year or of the summer,
而不是在学年或学期未
"oh you are great. You are terrific."
说"你很好 棒极了"
Really think about what these people,
真正用心去思考这些人
the important people in your life
你生命中的重要的人
are doing for you and express it.
为你做了什么 然后再表达出来
Don't take that for granted.
不要视之为理所当然
Don't take for granted that they know how grateful you are.
不要认为他们理应知道你心怀感激
"Yeah,of course mom knows.
"是的 妈妈当然知道
Of course dad knows that I'm grateful and they are terrific."
爸爸当然知道我感激他们 他们很棒"
Don't take it for granted. Express it.
不要视之为理所当然 表达出来
Again,write it in a letter or by phone or in person.
写信 致电或面对面说都可以
One of the most effective interventions out there today
当今最有效的一种干预形式
is expressing gratitude to others especially this one:
是向他人表达感激之情 尤其是这种方法
writting a letter of gratitude and then visiting the person to
写一封表达感激的信然后去拜访
whom you are writting and reading them the letter.
收信人 再把信读给他们听
Cheesy? I agree. A little bit embarrassing? Sometimes.
俗气? 同意 难为情? 有时是的
You cannot imagine the kind of result
你无法想像
that people get when doing just this gratitude visit.
人们做感激拜访时获得的结果
But even if you don't visit them,
但即使你不去拜访他们
you do feel self-conscious doing it. I do recommend it.
你觉得害羞 我建议去拜访
But you feel self-conscious,
如果你觉得害羞
send the letter,make that phone call.
那就把信寄出去再打电话
And before,just think for a few minutes,
致电前思考几分钟
"what am I going to say? What am I really grateful for?"
"我要说些什么?我到底感激什么?"
Again,whether it's to your parents,
不论是对你的父母
whether it's to your friends,
或朋友
whether it's to your 1st grade teacher. Just do it.
或是一年级老师 去做吧
Whether it's to your coach. The largest largest peak,boost,
或者是对你们的教练 表达感激时
spike in wellbeing when we are expressing gratitude to others.
是最让我们感到幸福的时候
Quite remarkable if you think about it.
想想吧 相当不可思议
And if you think about it further,it is a win-win.
进一步思考会发现它是双赢的
Because obviously you get the benefit-
因为显然你从中得益
this is what the research shows. We feel good when we express it.
研究已证明了这一点 表达感激时我们感觉很好
and the other person feels good too. They benefit a great deal.
对方也会感觉很好 他们的获益良多
So you are creating a win-win and an upward spiral,because
于是你创造了一个双赢的局面 一个上升的螺旋
that person is then more likely to express gratitude to others.
因为对方也更可能向他人表达感激
The best way to lead it by an example:
最好的方法是以身作则
be the change you want to see in the world,as Ghandi said.
成为你期许见到的改变 如甘地所说
So you want people to be more grateful?
想让他人充满感激?
Express gratitude yourself.
先以身作则表达感激
They are more likely to then take it on
他们才可能承接下去
and express gratitude to others. So not only you
向他人表达感激 你不仅仅
start an upward spiral between you and that person,
在你和对方之间启动了一个上行螺旋
but also potentially between that person as well as others.
对方和他人之间可以承接上行
Paying it forward. Paying it forward.
传递出去 传递出去
The downside of this intervention is
这种干预的不利之处是
while it leads to a spike in well-being,
虽然它能让幸福感达到峰值
that spike usually goes away after about a month.
但一个月后 幸福感会消退
It varies: it can go away after a week or after three months.
时间不同 可能是一周或三个月后
But the average it goes away after about a month.
但平均来说一个月后会消退
The spike to well-being.
幸福感的峰值
So the key you want to maintain the spike is to do it regularly.
保持这个峰值的关键就是经常去做
Either once a week. Once a week,two weeks. Once a month. Do it.
每周做一次 两周做一次或一月做一次
You can do it one week a gratitude phone call and make it ritual.
一周打一次感激电话 把它变成仪式
The next week,a gratitude letter.
下一周写信表达感激
The week after that,a gratitude visit. Or something like that.
再下一周 感激拜访 以此类推
Again,variety. Variety really helps here.
还是要有变化 形式的变化很有帮助
But do it regularly as a ritual.
但把它作为一种仪式经常去做
And when we talk about change next week,
下周谈"改变"时
we'll talk about the importance of rituals.
我们会谈到"仪式"的重要性
Because in many ways,
因为在很多方面
that's the only change for real,lasting change.
那是唯一的真正持久的改变
Here's one of the surprising findings
有一项惊人的发现
that Sonja Lyubomirsky found.
是Sonja Lyubomirsky的发现
What she found is that if we write that letter,
她发现如果我们写了那封信
we get the spike in wellbeing even if we don't send it.
就算不寄出去 幸福感也能达到的峰值
Obviously if we send it and we get feedback,
寄出去当然会得到回应
the spike is even higher.
峰值会更高
But just the act of writting it,of being grateful,being open,
但仅仅是书写 感受感激之情 敞开心扉
that in and of itself contributes to wellbeing. Next week,
这样做的本身也有助提升幸福感 下周
your response paper is going to be a letter of gratitude,
你们的功课就是一封感激信
which we will highly recommend you visit the person
我们强烈建议你们去拜访对方
and read it to them or,at the very least,
把信读给他们 或者最起码
send it if you are not close to them now physically.
把信寄出去 如果你们相隔很远
But even if you just write it
但即使是写了信
and don't feel comfortable sending it,
却不好意思寄出去
that in and of itself contributes to our wellbeing.
那同样能提升你的幸福感
I want to go a little bit more in depth into
我想再深入谈谈
how we express gratitude and in general,
如何表达感激 再概况谈谈
how we deal with painful and positive emotions.
如何应对痛苦和积极的情绪
Once again,Sonja Lyubomirsky did research,
再次引用Sonja Lyubomirsky所做的研究
while she invited participants to talk about
她邀请参与者谈论
or to share the worst experiences of their lives
分享生活中最糟的经历
and the best experiences of their lives.
和最好的经历
And what she did was divide them actually to four groups.
她所做的是把他们分成四组
One group- write about it.
第一组 写出来
Write about the ABC,the affect- the emotion,the behavior-
写出三方面 一是影响 也就是情感 二是行为
what you did then,and the cognition- what you thought then.
即当时你做了什么 三是认知 即当时的想法
Three times on three consecutive days for 15 minutes.
连续三天 每天一次 每次15分钟
First group just wrote about it.
第一组只是写出来
The second group talked about it to a tape recorder
第二组对着录音机说
about the same best experiences and another group,
讲述最好的经历 另一组
worst experiences.
讲述最糟的经历
Third group,just think about it-
第三组 只是去想
ruminate for 15 minutes also on three consecutive days.
连续三天 每天沉思15分钟
What she looked at was physical and mental health.
她观察他们身体和心理的健康状况
She looked at how healthy they were.
她观察他们的健康程度
She looked at their physical...
观察他们的身体
how they perceived themselves as healthy or not,
他们认为自己有多健康
how many symptoms they actually had.
他们有多少种病症
And she looked at their mood- how happy they were.
她还观察他们的情绪 他们有多快乐
Before the experiment and four weeks later,
观察期是实验前和实验后的四周
after that three days,15 minutes each day intervention.
经过三天 每天15分钟的干预后
There was also a fourth group,which was a control group.
还有第四组 是一个对照组
Here is what she found.
她的发现如下
So basically you have three or four by two,
一共有三或四组 每组作两项研究
writting,talking and thinking.
书写 谈论和沉思
Study one: worst experiences. Study two: best experiences.
研究一是最糟的经历 研究二是最好的经历
Those who wrote- let me just explicate this.
书写的人 我来解释一下
Those who wrote about the worst experiences actually felt better
书写最糟经历的人事实上感觉更好了
and were physically healthier,
身体上也更健康
compared to the control group four weeks later.
这是经过四周后与对照组相比的结果
Those who talked about it to a take recorder- remember?
对着录音机说的那些人 还记得吗?
about what they felt,about what they've been through,
谈论他们的感受 他们的经历
about what they thought at the time while they are thinking now.
谈论当时的想法和现在的想法
15 minutes,three days.
15分钟 连续三天
Actually,felt better after talking about it.
在谈论之后感觉更好了
Those who thought about it,
那些想的人
who ruminated about it,without talking,
沉思的人 不去谈论
without writting about it,actually felt worse
不去书写 他们感觉更糟了
and were physically less healthier a month later.
一个月后身体状况也更糟
The second study,
研究二
where they wrote about their happiest experiences,
他们书写最快乐的经历
we see the opposite trend. In other words,
我们看到相反的趋势 换言之
those who wrote about it on what they experience,
那些连续三天书写他们的经历
how they experience it,what they learn from it on three days,
如何经历以及汲取的教训的人
for 15 minutes each time,
每次15分钟
actually felt worse physically as well as mentally after a month.
一个月后身体和心理上都感觉更糟
Those who talked about it also about the ABC-
那些谈论这三样的人
the affect,the behavior,the cognition,
即影响 行为和认知
also felt better and were less healthy a month later.
一个月后同样感觉更好但身体状况更差
Well those who just thought about it,
而那些只是想的人
ruminated about their positive experiences,
沉思他们的积极经历的人
imagined it on three consecutive days,15 minutes each day,
连续三天 每天15分钟想像它的人
actually felt better and were healthier a month later,
一个月后感觉更好更健康
four weeks later. So she ran the third study to understand-
四周后的结果 于是她进行第三项研究去了解
this was a surprising result,was not what she expected.
这是很惊人的结果 出乎她的预料
So she ran the third study to understand the mechanism-
于是她进行第三项研究去了解其中的机制
what is going on here. Why is it that
这是怎么回事 为什么
when we write and talk about negative experiences,
当我们书写和谈论消极经历时
it makes us feel better and healthier?
我们会感觉更好更健康?
Strengthen our immune system?
增强我们的免疫系体?
Whereas when we just think about it,ruminate it,
但当我们思考或沉思时
what's going on here?
发生什么事?
Whereas the exact opposite is the case with positive emotions.
思考积极情感时却产生相反的结果
And what she found was there was a distinction
她的发现是
between analyzing and replaying.
分析和重现之间是有区别的
When we analyze an experience,
当我们分析一次经历时
when we make sense of it,it helps. It actually helps.
当我们理清它时 它真得有帮助
Painful experiences and negative experiences,
痛苦的经历和消极的经历
which is why therapy helps. And
所以心理治疗才有帮助
what helps in therapy more than anything is less of technique,
心理治疗中最有帮助的 除了技术
less the years of study that the therapists had,
除了心理治疗师的多年学习
less the experience that the therapists had. These things matter.
除了心理治疗师的经验 这些都很重要
But not that much. What matters most is are they empathic.
但不是最重要的 最重要的是他们的感同身受
In other words,are they good listeners? so
换言之 他们是不是好的聆听者?
when we feel like we can talk and analyze about painful emotion,
当我们觉得可以谈论或者分析痛苦情绪时
we feel better. We are physically healthier.
我们感觉更好 身体更健康
When we simply sit down
当我们只是坐下来
and ruminate about painful emotions without making sense of it,
沉思痛苦的情绪却不去理清它时
we get very often into a downward spiral.
我们经常进入下行螺旋
We narrow and constrict. We feel more sad.
我们收窄压缩 感觉更悲哀
We narrow and constrict even more.
进一步收窄压缩
Remember the Barbara Fredrickson's studies?
还记得Barbara Fredrickson的研究吗？
And so on and so on. In contrast,we are not sure why.
不断恶化 相反 虽然不清楚原因
when we analyze a positive experience,really analyze it-
当我们分析积极的经历时 真正地分析它
try to understand why it happened and so on.
尝试理解为什么会发生等等
So we do it for three consecutive days.
连续这样做三天
It actually dosen't help. We don't understand why.
它确实没有帮助 我们不明白为什么
But maybe it's because it takes all the fun spontaneity
也许是因为让我们回忆起
from the experience.
经历的快乐之处
However when we just ruminate about the positive experience-
但当我们只是沉思积极经历时
just think about it,then it contributes to our well-being.
只是想也会提升我们的幸福感
The gratitude exercise is about replaying the experience.
感激修习就是重播快乐经历
It's exactly that. In other words,
就是如此 换言之
it's thinking about our happiest experiences of the day,
就是说回想最快乐的日子
which leads ultimately to positive outcome.
能自动导致积极的结果
So what is it saying aobut the permission to be human?
那么准许为人说的是什么?
How is it different?
有什么区别?
Because the permission to be human is also very much related
因为准许为人也是为了
to being happier and healthier in the long term.
实现长期的快乐和健康
Well here's the difference: with the permission to be human,
区别是这样的 准许为人
we give ourselves the permission to experience the emotions
我们准许自己感受各种情绪
for as long as necessary.
只要有必要
If we just lost someone,it would be much longer
失去亲人时 我们准许自己感受情绪的时间
than if we just didn't perform so well in the test. But
远比考试失利的时间要长
we give ourselves the permission to experience the experience.
但我们准许自己感受经历
And then we ask ourselves,
然后我们自问
"so what would be the most effective way to act now?"
"现在最有效的行动是什么?"
And one fo the most effective way to act
最有效的行动之一
would be to share that experience.
是去分享那次经历
One fo the most effective way to act
最有效的行动之一
would be to just write in our journal. Daily active acceptance.
是写日记 接受每天的行为
Not just ruminating and staying there with this painful emotion.
不要苦苦沉思痛苦的情绪
Now one of the things I thought about it
我思考的一件事
also in the context of my grandmother's experience
也与祖母的经历有关
is why is it that- we'll talk about PTSD in a few minutes-
为什么会那样 一会我们会谈到PTSD
why is it that
为什么会那样
so many people in the United States coming back from Vietnam
从越南回国的很多美国人
30% of Vietnam vets experience post traumatic stress disorder.
30%的越战老兵都患有严重创伤后遗症
It affected their entire lives.
那影响了他们整个人生
Whereas people who have been through the holocaust,
但经历过大屠杀的人
no less terrible experiences,very often,much worse experiences,
同样是可怕的经历 经常是更可怕的经历
people who have been through the holocaust,percentage wise-
经历过大屠杀的人 就百分比来说
there are far less people who have PTSD-
患有PTSD的要少得多
post traumatic stress disorder. Why this difference?
严重创伤后遗症 为什么会有这种区别?
I mean,you know in Israel,50% of the older population-
我知道在以色列 50%的老年人
when I was born,50% of the population were holocaust survivers.
在我出生时 50%的人口都是大屠杀幸存者
I didn't see much post traumatic stress disorder there.
我没看到有很多严重创伤后遗症患者
Whereas again,30% of Vietnam vets have PTSD.
但30%的越战老兵都有PTSD
Now the jury is still out to see
现在陪审团正在调查
how many of the second Iraq war will come back with PTSD,
二次伊战老兵有多少患PTSD
but the number is going to be staggering too.
数字一定也很惊人
Why? What's the difference?
为什么? 为什么有这样的区别?
And I think this explains the difference.
我认为这就是解释
You see,Vietnam is not a popular war.
越战是遭到反对的战争
Many of the vets who came back to their home,
很多老兵回到家
to their country didn't talk about it openly.
回到家乡后 不会公开谈论它
They kept it inside them.
他们把经历藏在心里
And what they did was they were- right here-
他们所做的事情是 他们就在这里
thinking about some of the worst experiences,
他们反复回忆最可怕的经历
replaying it in their minds over and over and over again.
在脑海中反复播放
And the situation just worse and worse and worse.
结果情况越来越糟
In contrast,people coming from,
相反
again no less terrible experiences in the holocaust.
同样可怕的大屠杀的幸存者
They came back to their village.
他们回到自己的村子
They came back to their country.
回到自己的国家
They came to Israel and what did they do there?
他们去以色列 在那里做什么?
They talked about it.
他们谈论
They talked about their experiences- most of them,not all-
谈论他们的经历 多数人并非所有人
most of them talked about their experiences with their friends,
多数人会和朋友谈论他们的经历
with their family constantly talked about it.
和家人 不停地谈论
They were here. And over time,
他们在这里 随着时间推移
it helped them move on and continue.
这帮助他们继续生活下去
So the best advice from this study,you know that,
这项研究给出的最好建议 你们都知道
as I told you,
正如我所说
I am not going to teach you much new in this course.
这门课你们学不到太多新东西
Just want to remind you how helpful it is to have support group.
只想提醒你们 互助组的帮助有多大
How helpful it is to share with friends,with family,
与朋友 家人分享的帮助很大
with a therapist,with a journal,in writting-
和心理治疗师聊天 写日记 书写
we'll talk about journalling next week-
下周我们会谈到日记的作用
you know the most effective interventions both for positive
两者对积极和消极经历
as well as negative experiences-
都是最有效的干预形式
only we are writting in different way:
只是以不同的形式书写
one we analyze; the other,we simply replay.
一种是分析 另一种是简单的重播
Being grateful shouldn't wait for Thanksgiving.
表达感激不应该等到感恩节
We shouldn't wait just once a year,that November date,
我们不应该只等每年一次 在11月的那天
when we express gratitude,
去表达感激之情
when we go around the table and say what we are grateful for.
坐在桌旁轮流说感激什么
It should be a habit. A,because it works,it helps.
它应该是一个习惯 首先因为它行之效 有帮助
And B,because it's moral.
其次因为它是道德的
This gets to a point that I'll repeat throughout the course,
这点很重要 我会贯穿始终强调
where the moral is also the practical.
道德也是实际的
The practical,in most cases,is also the moral.
而实际在多数情况下 也是讲道德的
They go hand in hand. David Steindl-Rast,
两者密不可分 David Steindl-Rast
the book that I mentioned last time: "We live in a 'given" world.
上次课我提到的那本书"我们生活在一个给与的世界
What brings fulfillment is gratefulness,
带来满足的是感激之情
the simple response of our heart
心灵对此给与人生的简单回应
to this given life in all its fullness.”
就是圆满"
Again,just like a child. The poet,Galway Kinnel:
就像一个孩子 诗人Galway Kinnel写道
"To live and die in gratefulness,if in no other virtue."
"感激地活着和死去 若无其他美德"
Cicero: "Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues,
Cicero写道"感激不仅是最大的美德
but the parent of all others". Why is it parent of all others?
也是其他美德的发源" 为什么是其他美德的发源?
I thought about this sentence a lot which I love,but why?
我经常想起这句最爱的话 但是为什么?
Because if you think about it,if we are not grateful,
想想吧 如果我们不知感激
then we take things for granted.
我们就会将事情视作理所当然
If we are not grateful for the good things in our lives,
如果我们不知感激生命中美好的事物
things are taken for granted. And then we are blind to them.
认为它们理所当然 那就会对它们视而不见
Then as far as we are concerned,they do not exist.
对我们来说 它们是不存在的
Now what makes virtue virtuous? It's the good.
美德为什么是高尚的? 是它的好
And if there is no good in our world,
如果世上没有好
then that takes away the virtue from being virtuous.
那么美德将不再高尚
That is why I think...
所以我认为...
what Cicero was talking about when he meant
Cicero所谓的
"it is the parent of all virtues".
"它是所有美德的发源"的含义
Another concernment benefit finder is the Radcliff student,
另一个重要的积极者是雷德克利夫学院学生
or was a Radcliff student,Helen Keller.
曾经的雷德克利夫学院学生 Helen Keller
Helen Keller,quite literally,
Helen Keller
open our eyes and get us appreciate what is all around us.
能让我们睁开双眼感激周遭的事物
She tells us a story in her wonderful autobiography
她在精彩的自传中讲了一个故事
about a friend who came to visit her once in Cambridge.
关于一个曾去剑桥看望她的朋友
There were many more woods at the time.
当时还有很多树林
And the friend walked around the woods
那位朋友在树林里散步
and when her friend came back,Helen Keller asked her,
朋友回来时 Helen Keller问她
"so what did you see? What did you note?",
"你看到了什么? 留意到什么?"
to which her friend responded,"well,nothing in particular."
她的朋友回答说"没什么特别的"
And Helen Keller responds to that
Helen Keller在自传中
"nothing in particular" in her autobiography. Let me read.
对"没什么特别的"作出回应 我来念念
“I wondered how it was possible to walk for an hour
"我奇怪怎么可能在树林里
through the woods and see nothing of note.
走了一小时后 却什么都没看到
I who cannot see find hundreds of things:
我虽看不到却发现许多东西
the delicate symmetry of a leaf,
精美对称的叶子
the smooth skin of a silver birch,
银色白桦的光滑树皮
the rough,shaggy bark of a pine.
松树粗糙的树皮
I who am blind can give one hint to those who see:
我一个瞎子也能给看得见的人一个提示
use your eyes as if tomorrow you will have been stricken blind.
像明天就会瞎掉那样用你们的眼睛
Hear the music of voices,the songs of a bird,
听声音的乐曲 鸟的鸣唱
the mighty strains of an orchestra
一个管弦乐队的强劲弦律
as if you would be stricken deaf tomorrow.
仿佛明天你会突然聋掉
Touch each object as if tomorrow your tactile sense would fail.
像明天就会失去触觉那样触摸每样东西
Smell the perfume of flowers,taste with relish each morsel,
闻花朵的香气 品尝每一口的气味
as if tomorrow you could never taste or smell again.
仿佛明天你将永远失去味觉和嗅觉
Make the most of every sense.
充分利用每一种感官
Glory in all the facets and pleasures and beauty
每一面的美好 愉悦和美丽
which the world reveals to you."
这世界向你展现"
Take a minute twice a day to focus on what is going on around you
每天两次花一分钟时间留意周遭的一切
Take a minute when...
花一分钟的时间
on your way to class to look at the beautiful grass,
在上课的路上看看美丽的草地
the beautiful trees,the beautiful snow.
青翠的树 美丽的雪
Take a minute in the evening to reflect
晚上用一分钟去回忆
and think about the day you had,
回想你度过的一天
and to write down the things for which you are grateful.
写下让你心怀感激的事物
Today over lunch,
今天午餐时
just by a little bit slower than you do normally and taste,
略比平时吃得慢些去品尝
experience the taste.
体验品尝的滋味
Because it is a privilege to have the food that we have.
因为我们所吃的食物是种特权
It is a privilege to have the friends that we have.
朋友是我们的特权
the family that we have.
家人是我们的特权
And we shouldn't take that privilege for granted.
我们不应视特权为理所当然
Because what we don't appreciate unfortunately depreciates.
因为我们不知欣赏的就会贬值
We don't need to wait for a threat,for a tragedy,
我们不需要经历一次威胁 一出悲剧
for us to appreciate what's all around us and within us.
才去感激周遭和内心感受的一切
What reminds me constantly,my surrounding,
时刻提醒我的 我的周围环境
the reminder that I have always in front of my eyes,
时刻在我眼前提醒我的
is a picture of my family and particularly,
是我家人的一张照片
of my grandmother in the middle.
特别是中间的祖母
And here's my grandfather who saw her coming in stooped,
祖父看到她弯腰走进来
ill and took her into his arms. I have this picture in my office.
病倦不堪 他把她揽在怀中 我办公室里放着这张照片
Looked at it all the time to remind me.
经常看它来提醒自己
I would have told you the story now
我本可以现在给你们讲这个故事
which comes at the end of the lecture.
原本安排在讲座最后
But I know when I tell the story,it drains me so much.
但我知道讲完故事 我会心力憔悴
I don't think I would be able to go on.
我将无法继续讲座
So I told you at the end of the lecture last time.
所以我会在讲座最后讲这个故事
But this is my reminder.
但这是给了我一个提醒
This is what primes me,creating a positive environment-
它激励我创造一个积极的环境
primes me and reminds me to be a benefit finder.
激励提醒我要作一个积极者
So here is what I want to do now.
接下来我想做的是
What I want to do now is take a time in.
现在我想占用一点时间
The first time in of the semester,not the last one.
本学期第一次占用时间 不会是最后一次
Time in when you have a chance to look inside yourself,
占用一点时间让你们有机会审视自己
to reflect.
去反省
You'll have opportunity in sections as well.
分组时也有机会
I want to do it now in this room.
我想现在教室里做
I want you to take just a couple of minutes to think about
我要你们用几分钟时间回想
and write down mindfully the things for which you are grateful.
在脑子里记下来你所感激的事物
The wonderful things in your life. So take two minutes to do it.
生命中美好的事物 给你们两分钟时间
(Time in)
计时
Ok. It would be great if you continue this later on as well.
好 希望大家课后能继续
But I want to do something else now.
现在我想做另一件事
Something slightly embarrassing. My apologies in advance.
有点让人难堪的事情 我先表示歉意
But what I'd like you to do now
但我想让大家现在
is share with the person next to you some...
和你旁边的同学分享
You don't need to share everything.
不必分享所有事
And you can have some beeps in middle
可以隐去一些事情
if you want to have censorship. That's fine.
你想有保留 完全可以
But just take couple of minutes to share with one another,
用几分钟时间分享一下
with the person next to you or if there are three of you,
和身边的同学 如果是三个人
just share quickly.
简单快速地分享一下
I am just going to give you two minutes for that.
我给你们两分钟时间
The things for which you are grateful.
分享你们感激的事物
You can elaborate on one thing or you can read the list.
可以详细说一件事也可以读你列下的清单
(Students talking)
（学生在分享）
Take 30 secondes more. 30 secondes more to finish up.
再给你们30秒 30秒收尾
OK. OK. You... You can continue later.
好了 好了 大家可以课后继续
I recommend you continue later.
我建议大家课后继续
Very simple intervention that goes a long way.
很简单的干预却获益良多
If we just learn to focus on the positive,
只要我们能专注于积极的方面
we co-create the more positive reality. What I want to do now
就能同共创造更多积极的现实 现在我想做的是
before moving on to the next lecture on change.
在开始关于"改变"的讲座之前
I want to say a few words about the final project.
我想就期末报告说几句
Remember the idea of the final project
期末报告
is basically a presentation anywhere between 20 to 30 minutes
你们将要做的
that you will create.
是一次时间在20到30分钟的报告
This is both for the extention school
进修学院的同学
as well as for the college students.
和在校生都要做
20-30 minute presentation that you will hand in as,
20到30分钟的报告 而且要交上来
or about any topic within positive psychology.
积极心理学中的任何主题都可以
And by the way,
随便说一句
that could also be positive psychological interventions
也可以是用积极心理学干预
for depression or anxiety. It could be about gratitude.
治疗抑郁和焦虑 可以是关于"感激"的
It could be the mind body connection.
可以是关于身心联系
It could be about spirituality and religion.
可以是关于灵性和宗教
It could be about self-esteem.
可以是关于自尊
What I would urge you to do
我敦促大家去做的
is find the most personally meaningful topic
是找到对自身最有具意义的
that you want to research.
你想研究的主题
Remember what is the most personal is also most general.
记往最私人的也是最普遍的
So if you are very much interested,passionate in spirituality,
如果你对灵性问题很感兴趣很狂热
do that.
就写有关灵性的报告
If you really want to understand more
如果你想更好地理解
and be able to apply to your life more,
更好地应用于人生
positive psychological interventions for,I don't know,
把积极心理学干预用于解决 我不知道
public speaking anxiety or whatever it is,do it on that.
公开演讲焦虑症或其他问题 都可以
The more personal you get in that,in that paper,
报告内容对个人问题涉及的越多
the more you'll get out of it.
你从中得到的也越多
You'll hand it in as a written text.
你们要把书面报告交上来
20 to 30 minutes is about 10 to 15 pages of texts
20到30分钟的报告内容 大约要写10到15页
and this is what you'll ultimately hand in.
这是你们最终要交上来的
You'll give both a written text as well as slides.
既要交书面报告也要交幻灯片
We are not going to grade for how beautiful
我们不会因你的幻灯片
and how amazing your powerpoints...
有多漂亮多精彩而打分
But we do want you to hand in slides
但我们希望你们能提交幻灯片
that will be the outline for your talk.
那将作为你们报告的大纲
Now the only part of this that will be actually graded
打分的唯一部分
is what you hand in at the end,meaning the text of your lecture.
是你最后提交的东西 也就是你的报告的文稿
However,in addition to that,
但是除此
the powerpoint will be graded pass/fail,
幻灯片是必选项
meaning you have to do it.
就是说必须做幻灯片
but you are not going to be graded for it,
但幻灯片不会参与打分
is to give the presentation to other people from your section.
是给小组成员作的报告时用的
Those of you in extention school
进修学院的同学
will give to other people in your community.
将对社区的其他人作报告
The idea here is paying it forward.
这样做是为了传递出去
Getting an idea and doing it.
找到一个主题然后传递出去
That's how I actually started my speaking career.
我的演讲生涯就是这样开始的
I had a topic that I was personally interested
我自己有个感兴趣的主题
and I gave it to the squash team.
我给壁球队作了演讲
I talked about it. Just to people close to me.
我跟和我很亲近的人讲
And I had a topic and then that evolved over time.
我有了一个主题 最后发展成演讲
So we want you,for those of you who haven't had the experience
我们希望那些没有经历的同学
is to first of all synthesize material
首先去综合
in the topic that you care about,
你感兴趣的主题的资料
that you think will make a difference in your life;
那些能改变你人生的东西
and second to be able to pay it forward.
然后再传递出去
It has to have reference to research.
必须有参考书目
This is not just a personal story or an autobiography.
这不只是个人故事或自传
It has to have reference to research. In addition to,
必须有参考书目
of course stories that you think capture the point.
当然可以加上能突出你的论点的故事
Probabaly the most effective way of communicating an idea
最有效率的沟通方法
is through stories.
大概就是通过故事
You know,you'll probably not remember ten years from now,
十年后 你们也许不会记得
the research on self-efficacy. But you are much more likely
关于自我效能的研究 但你很可能
to remember the story of Roger Bannister.
记得Roger Bannister的故事
So people remember stories. They connect to stories.
人们记得故事 与故事产生联系
But at the same time,this is an academic paper.
但与此同时 这是一份学术报告
We want to brige the Ivory tower and the Main Street.
我们希望即有学术性又通俗易懂
So have references to research.
所以要有参考书目
And these are the things that would be optionally:
可以选择以下手段
you can have film clips- if you have a film clip in it,
可以截取电影片段 如果报告中有电影片段
it's a 10 minute film clip,
如果是十分钟的电影片段
it dosen't count as part of the 10 to 30 minutes.
它不会被计入报告时间
Especially if you have 20 minute film clip
尤其是当你截取20分钟电影片段时
unless you are giving a lecture,which is fine.
除非你准备来次讲座 那也可以
And include exercise.
要包括练习
So if this is a workshop,what exercise would you do?
如果这是个工作坊 你会做哪些练习?
Would you have,
你会让
you know participants express gratitude to one another?
参与者相互表达感激吗?
Would you have them writting a journal?
你会让他们写篇日记吗?
Would you have them go out and exercise physically later?
你会让他们在课后出去锻炼身体吗？
So include exercises as well. Here are the dates.
所以还要包括练习 下面是提交日期
So this is em... These are your deadlines,
这是...你们的最后期限是
or rather,your lifelines in this project.
或者说你们报告的生命线是
March 20th,just before spring break,
3月20日 在春假之前
all you need to do is let your TF know your topic.
你们只需要告知助教你们的主题
One word,one sentence- it's gratitude. It's spirituality.
一个字 一句话 "感激"也好 "灵性"也好
It's mind-body. Specifically physical exercise.
是"身与心" 身体练习 都可以
Just let them know.
通知他们一声
Now you may change that a week later or two weeks later.
一两周后 你们可以改主意
But we just want you to start honing and thinking about
我们只希望你们开始思考
what your likely topic will be. So that's March 20.
你最想做的主题 那是3月20日的任务
April 7- give you some time after spring break,
4月7日 让你们享受几天春假
so you don't have to work on it over spring break,
放假时不必操心课业
though we hope you'll at least think about it
虽然我们希望你们能抽时间思考
and read some stuff over spring break.
放假期间阅读些材料
April 7: one page outline. A draft of your topic.
4月7日交一页大纲 你的主题的草稿
Again,this is not graded.
这个也不计入分数
This is just for you,meaning pass/fail.
只是为你们自己 确认是否通过
So you have to hand it in. Just for you.
所以必须交上来 只是为了你们自己
Then you can talk to your teaching fellow about it. By May 3,
好让你们和助教商量 5月3日之前
give the presentation to at least three or four classmates.
向至少三到四位同学作一次报告
If you are in extention school,give it to other people.
如果你是进修学院学生 就给别人讲一次
And ask them for feedback.
征求他们提供意见
And you'll get feedback- ideally,written feedback.
得到反馈意见 最好是书面的
We'll talk to you about the process later on when the time comes.
到时我们会谈到具体的过程
Again,this is not graded. It's for you.
这个也不计入分数 只是为了你们自己
It's for you as well as for the participants,
既为你也为参与者
because you are paying it forward.
因为你们在传递
It can be a rough draft. It is a rough draft.
可以是一份草稿 就是一份草稿
And I'll give you feedback and say,
我也会给出意见
"you know,what I thought was missing is maybe an extra story
"我觉得还缺一个故事
or I felt like you were not grouded enough in research."
我感觉你的研究资料不足"
Or,you know,"introduce a little bit more energy."
或者"再加入更多活力"
Or whatever it is. Get feedback from them to help you.
不论是什么 向听众获取意见来帮助你
And then the week later,the final project will be due.
再过一周就是期末报告的截止日
Any questions about this? If you have a question,
有什么问题吗? 如果你有问题
probbably others have the same questions.
别人也可能有同样的问题
So any questions about the final project?
关于期末报告有任何问题吗?
Ok. Think about it. Yes. Question.
好的 想一想 请说
No,it's not in section. You will actually... Ok.
不 不是分组进行 其实你们会...好的
So the question is where do you make the presentation.
问题是你们在哪里作报告
You'll have to get together with your group,
你们会被分成组
the other three or four,probably be three.
和另外三到四个人 可能是三人一组
And give each other the presentation.
然后相互作报告
If you want to do it with powerpoints
想用幻灯片
and the whole thing,that's perfectly fine.
做完整的报告 非常好
If you just want to read it or speak it,
只想读或说出来
that's perfectly fine too.
也完全没有问题
Your choice is whatever you think would be most helpful to you.
可以选择对你最有帮助的方式
Again,this project is for you.
再强调一次 这个设计是为了你们自己
It's for you and for others hopefully
是为了你们自己 希望那些
who will benefit from hearing what you have to say.
听你报告的人也能从中受益
Students who have done it-
做过这个设计的学生们
we've already done it for the last two years.
过去两年我们一直有这么做
The first year I taught it- we just had a regular paper.
我教的第一年只提交了普通报告
And the students enjoy this process so much more
学生们非常喜欢这个过程
and get so much more out of it and it stays with them.
从中获益良多 他们保留了这种作法
Because it's something you can take,again,
因为你可以用这个方式
pay forward also when you are done here. Other questions? Yes.
在修完这门课后继续向外传递 还有问题吗? 是的
Dr. Tal Ben-Shahar:
塔尔宾夏哈尔博士
Yes. Good question.
是的 很好的问题
So are you supposed to narrow down a topic
是否要收窄到一个主题
as opposed to being very general life spirituality?
而不是笼统的人生灵性体验?
Up to you. Up to you. You can give an overview and then,
这完全看你们 你可以先概况
at the end of your presentation,say,you know,
在报告结束时再说
these are some of the interesting studies,
有一些很有趣的研究
but if you want more information,you know,
如果你们想了解更多
you can look there. Or you can do something very particular.
可以去那里找找 也可以做些特别的报告
So the benefit of church going.
比如去教堂的好处
Or the benefit of aerobic exercise.
或有氧锻炼的好处
It can be very specific or much more...
可以专注于一个主题也可以更笼统
Or the benefit,psychological benefit of Arabic exercise.
比如有氧锻炼的心理益处
So it can be very specific or very general.
即可以专注于一个主题也可以很概括
Up to you. Whatever you think would be more interesting to you.
由你们决定 只要你觉得更感兴趣
And what often happens when we found this is that
我们经常会发现
once you get into the literature,you are going through info-
当你们着手准备讲座 查资料
you'll read a lot of studies there. That's when you understand,
阅读很多研究时 那时你们才会明白
"OK,I have so much material on just this specific point
"仅就这个问题 我就有很多资料
I am going to focus here."
我准备专注这里"
Or I really want an overview of this whole topic.
或者我很想概述整个主题
And then in later presentations,
然后在后面的报告中
or I'll create a whole class just based on this topic later on.
或者我会在以后专注这个主题编一堂课
Or website. There are actually many students
或者网站 很多学生
who created websites based on their projects.
根据他们的报告开设了网站
There was another hand up there. Or were you just saying hi?
那里还有人举手 或者你只想问候一下?
Hi. Yes. They can't hear you.
是的 他们听不到你说的话
For extention students all over the world,
世界各地的进修学院的学生
you are going to pick two or three people anywhere,
你们可以在任何地方选两三个人
family,friends,
家人 朋友
whoever it is but people who will be "beautiful enemies" to you,
任何人都可以 但要是你的"美丽敌人"
who will give you real feedback.
他们会给你真实的意见
Because they care about you. Good. Alright. No one else?
因为他们关心你 好了 还有吗?
Alright,if you have further questions,
好的 还有问题的
ask your TF or ask me.
可以问你们的助教或问我
(A student sneezes.) Bless you.
祝你身体健康
Change. In many ways,
改变 可以说
we've been talking about change the whole class.
整门课都在讲改变
This class is about change,as I said on the first class,
这门课就是关于"改变" 我在第一堂课就说
I wouldn't be teaching it if I didn't think people could change.
如果我认为人不能改变 我就不会上这门课
And when I talk change,I am talking about different levels.
我说到改变时 我说的是不同的层次
Whether the change in terms of introducing a habit:
可以是培养一个习惯
I want to start exercising for three times a week. Why?
我想每周锻炼三次 为什么？
Because as you'll see from a few weeks from now,
因为几周后 你们会看到
exercising three times a week has the same effect
每周锻炼三次的效果
as some of our most powerful psychiatric drugs.
和很多有效的心理药物相同
Or let's say habit you want to introduce is you know,
或者你想培养的习惯是
I want to introduce spirituality to my life.
我希望人生的精神层面更丰富
Or change could be "I want to be happier".
改变也可以是"我想更快乐"
I want to experience less anxiety.
我希望不要那么焦虑
General anxiety or specific anxiety,before tests.
一般的焦虑或者特定的焦虑 例如考前
Whatever the change you want to introduce to in your life,
不论你希望生活有什么样的改变
there are certain patterns,certain approaches that work,
总有一定的模式和方法行之有效
certain approaches that don't work.
另一些方法行之无效
What we are going to do next two classes,
未来两堂课我们要做的是
two and a half classes is differentiate what works
两堂半课 是区分哪些行之有效
and what dosen't so that you can apply it to your life.
哪些行之无效 以便让你们将之应用于生活
So first of all,we've talked a lot about change.
首先 关于改变 我们谈过很多
Let's recap some of the things that we discussed.
让我们来回顾一下曾经讨论过的问题
First of all,on the second class we already mentioned this,
首先 在第二堂课上 我们已经提到
that change is hard.
改变很难
And there are a lot of studies to show how hard change is.
很多研究都证明了改变有多难
The twin research. Remember the conclusion.
双胞胎研究 还记得结论吗
Try and change your happiness is
尝试改变快乐水平
as difficult and futile as trying to change your height.
如同试图改变身高一样徒劳
Now even though they went back on their word and they said
虽然他们后来也说
"well it's not really impossible and futile",
"不一定是不可能和徒劳的"
still what they did show in their studies is that it is very hard
但他们的研究证明了很难做到
The twin studies. Happiness is a stochastic phenomenon.
双胞胎研究 快乐是一种随机现象
Then Daniel Gilbert's work on affective forecasting.
还有Daniel Gilbert的关于有效预测的研究
Yeah we experience it an up after we get tenure
在哈佛得到终身职位 或考入哈佛后
or after we get into Harvard,and we experience a down
我们的幸福感上升 当我们遭到拒绝时
when we are rejected by whatever it is. But
经历下行
then very quickly we go back up to our base level of wellbeing.
但很快我们又恢复到幸福感的基准线上
And most of our life
人生的多数时候
looks like this around this straight base level.
幸福感都是在基准线上下波动
It's very difficult to get an upward trajectory.
获得上升抛物线很难
It's possible through coping for example,but it's difficult.
通过去面对可能做到 但很难
The Cambridge-Somerville study-
剑桥-萨默维尔研究表明
5 year intervention that ultimately led to negative change,
五年的干预 最终导致消极改变
whether there's more alcoholism among the people
即使有最好的心理学家 心理治疗师
who did go through that intervention with bright in the best.
社工和各种计划进行干预
Psychologists,psychiatrists,social workers,programs.
实验人群中还是有更多人酗酒
So we know change is hard,
我们知道改变很难
whether it's on the individual level or on the society level.
不论是个人还是社会层面
However,we also know the change is possible.
然而我们也知道改变是可能的
We know that many of the people who argue that change
我们知道很多人争辩说
is not possible are making the error of the average,
改变是不可能的 他们犯了普遍性的错误
looking at the average score as opposed to outlayers,
只看平均分而不看例外情况
as opposed to people who have introduced change.
不看那些实现改变的人
And when we study change,it's the exception that proves the rule
当我们研究改变时 是例外证明了改变是可能的
So if change is possible and some people have been able to change
如果改变是可能的 有些人实现了改变
whether it's through therapy,whether it's by reading a book,
或者是通过治疗 读一本书
whether it's being a part of the class,
参加学习
whether it's through conversation-
或者是通过交谈
sometimes it's a single sentence
有时只需要一句话
that makes a difference to their entire life,
就能改变他们的整个人生
they are the exceptions. But
他们是例外
the questions are no longer whether or not change is possible.
但问题不再是改变是否可能
The question is "how is change possible".
问题是"如何才能实现改变"
And this is the question we are going to address in much greater
这个问题我们将在讲座中
depth on a higher level of the spiral in these lectures.
更深入在更高层次上讲
What does change look like? Let's go micro here.
改变是什么样的? 我们从微观上说
Let's go to the brain level. How does change actually look like?
去到大脑的层面 改变到底是什么模样的?
What happens in our brain when change occurs? Until 1998,
改变发生时 我们的大脑有什么变化? 直到1998年
neuro scientists thought that the brain was essentially fixed.
神经科学家认为大脑是不变的
We are born with certain neurones,certain pathways.
我们生来具有一定的神经元 一定的通道
The brain doesn't grow,dosen't change pass the age of,say three
大脑在三岁之后不会生长 不会改变
Maybe first a few experiences the brain still changes and evolves
开始时大脑可能会改变发展
But after the age of three,no change.
但三岁之后 不会再改变
And this theory which was held until 1998-
这个理论直到1998年仍站得住脚
I mean that's not so long ago,this theory gave credence,
也就是在不久以前 这个理论让人相信
and actually proved positive for
并实际证明了
"happiness is a stochastic phenomenon".
"快乐是随机现象"的正确
You are born with certain genes.
你生来具有一个的基因
You are born with certain inclinations
生来具有一个的倾向
with certain neurone pathways.
具有一定的神经元通道
You have a few experiences that really affect you a great deal,
有一些经历对你产生深刻影响
as Freud argued. And then the rest of your life,
正如弗洛伊德的论点  而剩下的人生
you are going to just fluctuate around that same level.
就是围绕那个水平波动
No change. That was until 1998. In 1998,
不会改变 直到1998年
scientists started to notice that the brain actually does change.
科学家开始发现大脑其实是改变的
And they came up with the concept of neuroplasticity.
并得出神经可塑性的概念
Neuroplasticity are nuerones are plastic- they change.
神经可塑性是指神经元有可塑性 它们会改变
Not only that,not only do the pathways change in the brain-
不仅如此 不只大脑的通道会改变
and we'll look at it in a minute,
一会我们就会看到
but also they've come up with another concept,
他们还得出另一个概念
which is neurogenesis. Neurones develop,
即神经形成 神经元是发展的
are created throughout our lives until the day we die potentially
在人的一生中不断生成 直到我们死去
So it's not the fact that
因此 事实并不是
we are born with certain number of neurones
我们生来具有一定的神经元
and it's downhill from there,
然后就一直走下坡
as conventional wisdom had us to believe-
传统的认识让我们相信这种说法
as many people still believe today.
今天仍有很多人相信这种说法
No,neurones are developed and grow,emerge throughout our lives.
不 神经元是发展生长的 在人生过程中不断出现
The brain,it turns out,in many ways is like muscle:
原来大脑在很多方面很像一块肌肉
use it and you don't lose it. Use it and you generate,
使用它就不会失去它 使用它能让它再生
you build the muscle up. And the question is
让肌肉更发达 问题是
how do we use it so that it becomes an assistant in a way,
要如何使用它 才能让它帮助我们
help toward becoming happier.
变得更加快乐
So let's look at what the brain actually look like.
我们来看看大脑到底是什么样子的
What it looks like is that there are millions of channels inside,
大脑里有数以百万计的通道
neural pathways,connections between different neurones in brain
神经通道 不同神经元在大脑里的连接
that look something like this.
看上去就像这样
As you can see,some are very thin,are relatively new.
你们能看到有些很薄 是新生的
some are much thicker,much more established.
有些更厚 更健全
And the way it works in many ways is like in nature.
它作用的方式很像自然界
You have large rivers,large channels.
即有大河 宽敞的渠道
And you have tiny rivers and tiny channels.
也有小河 狭窄的渠道
And what happens is that
原理是这样的
every time a connection is made between neurones- in other words,
每次神经元之间发生联系 换言之
your thought pattern follows a certain path.
你的思维模式有特定的路径运作
That path grows.
那个路径会成长
Just like a river- every time the water passes there,
像河流一样 每次有水流过
it gets this much,this much wider.
河流都会变得宽一些
And when there is no water there,
没有水的时候
there is no work being done in the neurone,
神经元不工作时
metaphorically speaking,it shrinks a little bit.
打个比方 它会萎缩一点
So neural pathways grow with use
使用时神经通道得到扩展
and they shrink when there is no use.
不使用时就会萎缩
If it's something new,a new neural pathway that
如果一条新的神经通道刚刚生成
was just created because remember- there's neuroplasticity.
因为神经是有可塑性的
Neural pathways are created constantly. There is neurogenesis.
神经通道不断生成 因为有神经形成
New neutrones are created constantly. Initially it's very thin.
新的神经元不断生成 开始时很薄
Let's say for example,I study French. And I learn a new word.
举个例子 我学法语 学了一个新词
A new connection is made in my brain.
我的大脑里形成新的联系
Now if I hear the word once and never again,
如果我只听了这个词一次
the neural pathway will disintegrate,will disappear. However,
神经通道会分裂 会消失
if I continue hearing that word over and over and over again,
如果我不断重复听到那个词
after all it will become thicker and thicker.
最后通道会变得越来越厚
Ok this is a way over simplification of the real process.
我说的比实际过程简化得多
But it will become thicker.
但它会变得更厚
And then I'll remember it for the rest of my life.
我就会一生记得这个词
It will be established like a river that is established,
就像形成了一条新的河流
as opposed to a tiny stream and trickle
不再是涓涓流淌的小溪
that can disappear in a day.
可能在某一天消失
And here is the key aspect for understanding
这是我们理解改变思维的
how we can change our thought,
关键方面
how we can change our wellbeing ultimately.
并最终提升我们的幸福感
The neural pathways are self-reinforcing,just like rivers are.
神经通道会自我巩固的 像河流一样
Think about it: when it rains,when there is a down pour,
想一想 下雨时 下倾盆大雨时
the water gravitates toward the existing river,
水流向已有的河流
toward the channels,toward the drains that we have built.
流向渠道 流向我们建好的沟渠
It's much less likely to create a new river
如果之前什么都没有
or a new stream with there's nothing before.
那么形成一条河流或小溪会更难
So the experience is much likely to gravitate to
我们的经历也更倾向于流向
already established neural pathways and strengthen it further,
已建成的神经通道并进一步加固它
as opposed to create new neural pathways,
而不是生成一条新的神经通道
which is why if we want to remember something,
所以如果我们想记住什么东西
it's very good to make connections to other things,
和其他东西产生联系是个很好的方法
to existing neural pathways,to existing memories.
和已有的神经通道 已有的记忆产生联系
Let me explain this again,
让我再解释一次
because this is important to understand.
理解这一点很重要
Because understanding this can actually...
理解这一点 其实...
this is something that Carol Dweck,professor at Stanford showed
这是Carol Dweck 斯坦福的教授的研究结论
and understanding this neuroplasiticity,
理解神经可塑性
understanding how we actually can change can make us
理解我们如何实现改变
more likely to succeed in one of the ways of success-
能让我们更容易成功
to actually become happier. So it's important to understand.
能让我们更加快乐 理解这一点很重要
And established neural pathway attracts more action
已建成的神经通道吸引更多活动
and it attracts more action and gets thicker.
从而变得更厚
Something that's not established,
没有建成的通道
a tiny little stream is more likely to be just wiped away.
一条小溪更容易消失
As it grows more,it's more likely to stay,
当它变得更宽 就更可能保留下来
not just stay,grow even more.
不仅保留下来而且能继续生长
It is self-reinforcing. And this is what habits are.
它是自行巩固的 习惯就是如此
When something is reinforced over and over again,
一种做法被反复巩固
it becomes a habit. For example,you play tennis
就变成一种习惯 比如打网球
and you hit the forehand over and over and over again.
你反反复复运用正手击球
Initially you have to think about it. You have to concentrate.
开始时你要考虑怎么打 必须集中精神
You have to,you know,maybe cock your wrist a little bit,
手腕翘起来一点
maybe understand exactly where you stop the racket,
知道球拍应该停在哪里
but after a while, after doing it hunderds of, thousands of times
但一段时间之后 挥过几百几千次后
you don't need to think about it anymore.
你不用再考虑怎么打
It's already grooved. And the word that I used is grooved,
它已经刻成槽 我使用"刻成槽"这个词
specifically because you essentially created a new channel.
因为事实上你创造了一条新渠道
And whenever a ball comes toward you,
只有有球飞过来
automatically you don't even need to think about it.
你不需要再考虑
It gravitates.
它被吸引
Your mind gravitates toward that particular path or paths,
你的思维被引向那个或那些特别的通道
many paths that tell you "lift it up and hit".
很多通道 告诉你"举起球拍击球"
It's automatic. Same with music.
完全是自动的 音乐也是如此
And what it has shown is people who practice music regularly
经常练习演奏的人
or practice a sport regularly,
或经常练习一种运动的人
their brain actually changes its shape.
他们的大脑真的会改变形状
More neural pathways are created around these areas
更多神经通道在那个区域形成
that mean "let me play a C now"
"让我演奏C调"
or "let me move my fingers in this way"
"让我的手指这样移动"
based on somthing that I see on the page.
根据我看到的乐章
Certain neural pathways are created,
特定的神经通道被创造出来
and the brain actually becomes thicker in these areas.
大脑在那些区域变成更厚
Or more experience flow in: the more we do it,the more they flow
更多经验流入 做得越多 经验流入的越多
Until it becomes grooved
直到它变成沟槽
and I don't need to think about how to play C-.
让我不需要考虑就能演奏降C调
It's automatic. They did a research.
完全是自动的 他们做过一项研究
This was the first research,one of the first research projects
这是做过的首批研究中的一项
where they found the brain actually changes.
让他们发现大脑其实是改变的
They took taxi drivers or freshly minted taxi drivers from London
他们让伦敦的出租车司机或新手司机
And what they had to do,to become,to get their certificate,
他们如果想获得执业证
their approval,they had to study the map of London.
他们的许可 他们必须学习伦敦地图
Now the map of London is much more complicated
伦敦地图
than study the map of New York.
比纽约地图复杂得多
Those of you who have been to London.
去过伦敦的人都知道
But they studied and they spent a lot of time.
但他们花很多时间研究地图
What they found was the brain,
他们发现司机们的大脑
part of their visual cortex actually changed from
他们的视觉皮质的一部分发生变化
before they started to study the maps of London to after.
在司机学习伦敦地图前后
Because they were working that part of the brain.
因为他们在使用那部分大脑
They had experiences.
他们有经验
And these experiences created grooves inside their brain,
这些经验在大脑中形成沟槽
so when someone said "Oxford Circus",immediately they knew
当有人说"牛津广场"时 他们立即知道
what street they need to take to Oxford Circus.
要走哪条街才能去到牛津广场
Their brain actually became bigger.
他们的大脑变得更大
It changed their neuroplasiticity. And that's wonderful news.
那改变了他们的神经可塑性 那是个好消息
It's really wonderful news. Because it means we have control.
是非常好的消息 那意味着我们可以控制
And we can introduce change.
我们可以引入改变
Now in our brain,there are both healthy and unhealthy pathways.
在大脑中既有健康通道也有不健康的
So for example,
比如说
some of the negative channels may be one of the constant worrier-
一些消极的通道 一个总是忧心重重的人
someone who worries a lot. That every time something happens,
一个事事担心的人 只要有事发生
immediately they gravitate to
他们立即转向
"ok so what does that mean for the future?"
"那对未来意味着什么?"
Or "what does that mean now for my prospects?"
"那对我的期望意味着什么?"
"What does it mean for today?" Constantly worrying about things.
"那对今天意味着什么?" 时刻担心各种事情
Even good things very often.
甚至经常为好事担心
They immediately interpret it as something to be worry about.
他们会立即把好事理解成需要担心的事
Or fault finding. That's pathways in the brain where I look for-
或者发现缺陷 消极思维会通过那条大脑通道
again they are self-reinforcing-
再说一次 通道是自行巩固的
I begin to look for in my world things that go wrong.
我会通过那条通道不断寻找我的缺陷
Remember my personal experience
我还记得自己的亲身经历
where I got the fellowship as a senior here.
当我获得本校的奖学金时
And I got the fellowship and immediately my brain gravitated
我得到了奖学金 但我的大脑立即开始想
toward "Ok but why didn't I get the other one?"
"但我为什么没得到另一个?"
I had so many things to be grateful for.
我有那么多事情值得感激
But it's the fault finder immediately the neural pathway,
但作为消极者 神经通道
the river this experience fell into was the largest one.
经验流向的河流是条最大的河
And the largest one for me at that time was being a fault finder.
当时对我来说 最宽的河流就是消极的
Then there are positive channels as well.
也有积极的渠道
What are the positive channels? Benefit finder. A person
积极的渠道是什么? 积极者
who is able to find benefit even in the hard circumstances.
一个即使在困难环境也能发现恩惠的人
May not say that the things happen for the best,
也许不会说塞翁失马 焉知非福
but something,but people made the best of things happen.
但他会从发生的事情中寻找恩惠
The optimist.
乐观主义者
Again,much larger,much wider channels for optimism.
乐观主义的渠道更大更宽
And the experiences gravitate toward there.
经验流向那里
Today we know much more how the brain works.
今天我们对大脑的认识更多
And where these channels exist?
这些渠道存在在哪里?
so let me give you an example of the one of the things we know.
我给大家举个众所周知的例子
One of the things that we know is that people
我们都知道
who have more action on the left side of the prefrontal cortex,
经常使用左侧前额皮质的人
compared to the right side of the prefrontal cortex,
和经常使用右侧前额皮质的人相比
are general happier. More susceptible to positive emotions,
要更快乐 更易受积极情绪的影响
more resilient in phase of painful emotions.
对痛苦情绪的适应性更强
More activation here- prefrontal cortex,
前额皮质这部分的活动更多
compared to the right side of the prefrontal cortex.
与右侧前额皮质相比
People who have more activation on the right side compard to
右侧活动更多的人
the left of f the prefrontal cortex are generally more depressed.
和左侧活动更多的人相比要更压抑
Now we know that today because we have FMRI,
今天我们知道这些 是因为有功能性磁共振成像
because we have EEG.
因为我们有脑电图
We can see how much the brain works on each side.
能看到大脑两侧的运作
But we knew that already hundreds of years ago.
但几百年前 我们已经知道这一点了
We knew that this side is associated with positive emotions,
我们知道这边与积极情绪有关
and more activation on this side of the front,
前额皮质这侧的活动越多
is associated with painful emotions.
与痛苦情绪相关联
How? Because when people,for example were in an accident,
怎么知道的? 因为人们发生意外时
and the accident happened to them
意外发生在他们身上
and the left side of the prefrontal cortex was damaged,
左侧前额皮质受损时
very often they became more depressed.
他们经常变得更抑郁
Because they had more activation on the right side as a result.
因为右侧的活动更多
In comparison,
相比而言
people who had an accident on the right side on the other hand,
另一方面如果意外发生在右侧
on the right side,very often,became happier.
右侧受损 人们经常会变得更快乐
Now I don't recommen this as an intervention.
我不建议以此为干预方法
Don't try it at home without your parents or with your parents.
不管有没有父母在家 都不要在家尝试
However,if you walk in the street,and you happen to fall,
但是如果走在街上 碰巧摔倒
it's always better to fall this way. So just keep that in mind.
最好往这边摔 大家记往了
Important thing to keep in mind then is that
需要记住的更重要的事是
very often the same trigger causes very different reactions.
相同的刺激往往造成不同的反应
Again the world is not just the external world.
世界不只是外在世界
It's also the internal world.
还有一个内在世界
Remember to the same mind,as Emerson said,
记往对同一个头脑来说 正如爱默生所说
the same world can be... or to the different minds,
同样的世界...对不同的头脑来说
the same world can be a heaven or a hell.
同样的世界即可能是天堂也可能是地狱
Depends on what that experience gravitates toward.
要看那种经验流向哪里
Over the years,I've become a  much more,
多年来 我变得
much more of a benefit finder through the exercise,
更像一个积极者 通过修习
through thinking about it,by writting,keeping a journal,
通过沉思 通过书写 写日记
by physically exercising,I become much more of a benefit finder.
通过身体锻炼 我变成了积极者
I've done a lot of work in that.
为此我付出很多努力
One of the great fortunes in my life is that
我人生最大的财富
I married a consummate benefit finder.
是我娶了一个完美的积极者
Tommy,my wife doesn't have to work that hard at it.
我的妻子Tommy 她不需要后天的努力
So for example,we would come back from a party.
举个例子 我们参加一次派对回来
And there was someone at the party who couldn't stop talking.
派对上有个人一个劲地说话
Have you encountered a person... Well,couldn't stop talking.
你们遇到过吗...一个说个不停的人
And I just about to tell Tommy you know,
我正要和Tommy抱怨
this person just couldn't shut his or her mouth.
说个人就是个话痨
And what would she say before I open my mouth? She said,
她在我开口前说了什么? 她说
"see how wonderful that person was
"你看那个人多好
and he or she is so passionate about what they do?"
他对所做的事是如此热情?"
So for me,it was talkative. For her,it was passion.
在我眼中多话 在她眼中是热情
Again,automatically going there.
她自动地发现恩惠
There is a genetic set point- and we'll talk about the genes-
这里有基因因素 我们会谈到基因
that lead some people to be much more benefit finders than others
让某些人比其他人更善于发现益处
But at the same time,we can work on it.
但与此同时 我们可以加以培养
We can work on it,pathway by pathway. And
我们可以一条通道一条通道地塑造
what we are doing there is quite literally transforming the brain
我们所做的就是改变大脑
We'll talk about during the week on mindfulness meditation
我们会在讲到"念"和"冥想"时讲这个问题
that meditation- for instance regular yoga- actually makes our..
冥想 比如经常做瑜珈
changes the pathwaya in our brain,
能改变我们大脑里的通道
makes it more active on the left side compared to the right side.
让左侧相比右侧更活跃
Makes it more susceptible to positive emotions,
让我们更易受到积极情绪的感染
more resilient to the phase of painful emotions.
对痛苦情绪有更好的承受力
We can change the brain. Neuroplasiticity and neurogenesis.
我们可以改变大脑 利用神经可塑性和神经形成
We are going to talk about two types of change in this next week.
下周我们会谈到两种类型的改变
The first type of change is the gradual approach.
第一种是渐进的改变
This is the change of gradually chipping away excess stone.
这种改变是一点点凿掉多余的石头
This is the change that
这种改变
we see in nature with the water sweeping away the stone,
就像自然界的水冲刷石块
making it thinner over time,making it smoother.
历经时日 让石块变得更薄更光滑
The gradual change. This is the change we mostly see in the world
渐进的改变 这是世上最常见的改变
It's the healthy change. There is no quick fix. It takes time.
这是健康的改变 没有捷径 需要时间
However,the change process can be as enjoyable as the outcome.
然而改变的过程可以和结果一样让人享受
Think about how to learn to play musical instrument.
想想学习演奏乐器
It takes time. It's by the way the same process,
它需要时间 是相同的过程
because we are creating new neural pathways in our brain,
因为我们在大脑里创造新的神经通道
when we are learning musical instrument.
当我们学习演奏乐器时
We can enjoy the process that ten years
我们享受十年的学习过程
that it takes us to get to play in a concert in Leverett JCR.
最后在Leverett学生社交室里举办的音乐会上演奏
We can enjoy the process of getting there before we are there.
我们可以享受最后站在台上演奏前的乐趣
So the change process in and of itself can also be fun.
所以改变本身也可以很有趣
We can enjoy the journey as well as the destination.
我们即能享受过程也能享受结果
It takes time. A lot of time.
它需要时间 很多时间
Then there is also the acute approach to change.
也有实现改变的剧烈方法
You know if the metaphore for the gradual change
如果用水冲刷石头
was the water breaking down stone,
来比喻渐进的改变
the metaphore for acute approach is taking a sledgehammer
可以用拿大锤
and breaking the water,breaking the stone.
砸石头来比喻剧烈的改变
You know what Moses did. The acute change.
就像摩西那样 剧烈的改变
Takes... Dosen't take much time. It happens immediately.
不需要太多时间 立即发生
But the important thing to keep in mind,
但要记住的重要的一点是
with the acute change is it's not a quick fix. The acute change,
剧烈的改变不是一步奏效 剧烈的改变
very often,takes a lot of preparation,metaphorically speaking-
经常需要很多准备功夫 打个比方
You need a lot of strength to pick up the hammer
你需要很多力气去挥大锤
and to have the power to put it down.
还要有力气砸下去
So it takes time. Both take time.
所以也需要时间 两者都需要时间
And that's important to keep in mind. Why? Martin Seligman:
记往这一点很重要 为什么? Martin Seligman说过
“The belief that we can rely on shortcuts to gratification
"相信有捷径通向满足
and bypass the exercise of personal strengths
绕过个人力量和美德的训练
and virtues is folly. It leads to legions of humanity
是很蠢的 它导致很多人
who are depressed in the middle of great wealth
在坐拥巨大财富时感到抑郁
and are starving to death spiritually."
精神饥渴而死"
This is one of the main reasons
这是当今世界不快乐的
for the unhappiness in the world today. I alluded to it
一个主要原因 我先提示一下
but I want to elaborate it a little bit more before we end.
我会在结束前多讲一些
How many here have read,by the way,
有多少同学读过
the Seven Habits of Highly Effective People,Stephen Covey.
Stephen Covey的《高效能人士的七个习惯》
Ok. Quite a few. It's a wonderful book.
好 不少同学读过 很好的一本书
One of the best,if not the best self-help books out there.
就算不是最好也是其中之一的自励书
Stephen Covey at the beginning of the book
Stephen Covey在书的开头
talks about the research that he did for his PHD.
谈到他的博士论文的研究课题
And what he did was look
他所做的是
at the success literature of the last 200 years.
看过去200年来成功学著作
And what he found was that there was a real cut-off point in 1930
他发现1930年是个分界线
Until 1930,19th century and the beginning of the 20th century,
1930年之前 19世纪和20世纪初
self-help was about character change.
自励在于性格改变
It was about changing who you are from inside.
从内在改变自己
It was about struggling in hard work and failing and going,
需要努力挣扎 跌倒再爬起
getting up again. Going through hardships.
经历苦难
And changing step by step,slowly,gradually.
一步步地改变 缓慢渐进地实现
1930- radical change. From character change,it became quick fix.
1930年剧烈改变 从性格改变变成一步奏效
Thinking grow rich.
想发财
How to win friends in influent people. Do it now.
如何结交权势 现在就做
The secret- quick change,immediate change,easy change.
秘密就是 快速改变 立即改变 轻易的改变
And from the 1930s,
1930年代以来
what we see is a decline in people's level of well being.
我们看到人们幸福感不断下降
Much more depression. Much more anxiety.
人变得更加抑郁 更加焦虑
And one of the reasons is that.
其中一个原因就是
That people hope and believe that they can find quick fix.
人们希望相信他们能发到一步奏效的办法
There is no quick fix. It takes time. It takes time to change.
没有一步奏效的办法 需要时间去实现改变
However,the change process can be as enjoyable,
但改变的过程可以是很享受的
as fun,as exciting as ultimately achieving the change.
如同最终实现改变一样乐趣无穷 令人兴奋
And next week we'll talk about that wonderful process.
下周我们就会谈到这个美妙的过程
Have a good weekend.
祝大家周未愉快